<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on tertium quid</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on tertium quid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>scientific method</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/scientific_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/scientific_method/</guid>
      <description>More of a branding ploy than a description of how science is done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fusion illusion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/fusion_illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/fusion_illusion/</guid>
      <description>Tritium-fueled reactors will never deliver power to the grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>life-organizing principles 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/life_organizing_principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/life_organizing_principles/</guid>
      <description>Would that more people applied these simple directives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Nagel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/thomas_nagel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/thomas_nagel/</guid>
      <description>A brief introduction to the key ideas of this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uncivilization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/dark_mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/dark_mountain/</guid>
      <description>Our technological civilization is not sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quantum Hall emergence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/quantum_hall_emergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/quantum_hall_emergence/</guid>
      <description>A ChatGPT essay</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the Alexander material</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/alexander_material/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/alexander_material/</guid>
      <description>A ChatGPT compilation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Reductionism and Its Entanglement with Materialism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/reductionism_materialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/reductionism_materialism/</guid>
      <description>Reductionism—the idea that complex phenomena can be explained by reducing them to simpler components—has shaped the trajectory of modern science. Over time, it became tightly coupled with materialism (and its modern cousin, physicalism), forging a dominant paradigm for understanding the natural world. This article traces the evolution of reductionism, from its mechanistic roots to its contemporary reassessment.
The seeds of modern reductionism were sown in the 17th century during the Scientific Revolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spiritual frameworks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/spiritual_frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/spiritual_frameworks/</guid>
      <description>Is the world, reality, very, very different from what most of us have been taught through modern science? Could non-physical properties (mind, spirit, or other) Provisionally interchangeable terms include mind, spirit, Tao, be as fundamental as charge or mass? Can ancient traditions and mystical perspectives contribute to a more complete picture of the way the universe really is than our current physicalist conception?
According to the scientific models, explanations and narratives that dominate contemporary Western thought, the answer to these questions is a resounding &amp;ldquo;No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>classical worldview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/classical_worldview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/classical_worldview/</guid>
      <description>A 17th century worldview continues to dominate much of science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>full humanness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/full_humanness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/full_humanness/</guid>
      <description>A.H. Maslow coined a number of terms that have come into common parlance beyond academic psychology , including &amp;ldquo;hierarchy of needs&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;self-actualization&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;peak experience&amp;rdquo;. In his last book, The Farther Reaches of Human Nature, Maslow uses the term &amp;ldquo;full humanness&amp;rdquo; to describe psychologically healthy and mature people&amp;ndash; those who are self-actualized and beyond. But what defines a self-actualized person? And what lies beyond self-actualization?
Maslow understood the inherent difficulty of explicitly answering such subjective questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physicalism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/physicalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/physicalism/</guid>
      <description>Download PDF version “The most important and exceedingly difficult task of our time is to work on the construction of a new idea of reality.”
— Wolfgang Pauli
Almost a century after the initial discoveries of the quantum nature of matter, and many decades after they were confirmed beyond serious question, even many well-educated people do not know that quantum physics appears to have upended a conception of reality that has been in place since the 17th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>panpsychism 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/panpsychism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/panpsychism/</guid>
      <description>Mind all the way down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix Affirmations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/phoenix_affirmations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/phoenix_affirmations/</guid>
      <description>Download PDF version Christianity has gone through a number of significant metamorphoses over the last two millennia, some of them radical enough to permanently change the nature of the West&amp;rsquo;s foremost religion. Another radical change is beginning to swell through the sea of mainstream Christianity as increasing numbers of thoughtful Christians challenge the prevailing doctrines of separation and exclusion, preferring instead to focus on the personal change that comes from a sincere attempt to emulate the life of Jesus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>metaphysics of science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/metaphysics_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/metaphysics_science/</guid>
      <description>Science cannot escape metaphysics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/dolphin_rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/dolphin_rights/</guid>
      <description>Reprinted from The Dolphin Embassy, November 2017
Based on a wealth of scientific research and evidence that cetaceans have intellect, feelings, culture and a complex social system;
Taking into account the growing international movement for the protection of cetaceans;
Taking into consideration the numerous precedents in this field (national laws on the banning or non-expansion of aquariums, declarations on the recognition of dolphins and whales as non-human individuals, the creation of international marine nature reserves for dolphins and whales);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/einstein_bohr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/einstein_bohr/</guid>
      <description>One of the most fascinating debates in scientific history was the ongoing disagreement between Albert Einstein and Neils Bohr about reality and quantum theory, particularly between “realists” and those who accepted the Copenhagen Interpretation (CI) proposed by Bohr.[1] Einstein was am unwavering realist; he believed that there is a fundamental, knowable reality at the base of all things– if only you know enough about it. “God does not play dice with the world”, one of Einstein’s famous quotes, sums up his refusal to believe that probability was the fundamental basis for physical reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Article</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/test_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/test_article/</guid>
      <description>Here is a sidenote. Just testing. Here is a second sidenote. Just testing. Here is a third sidenote. Just testing. Here is a fourth sidenote. Just testing. Here is a sidenote. Just testing. Here is a second sidenote. Just testing. Here is a third sidenote. Just testing. Here is a fourth sidenote. Just testing. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
