<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>practices on tertium quid</title>
    <link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/categories/practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in practices on tertium quid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/categories/practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>life-organizing principles</title>
      <link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/life_organizing_principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/life_organizing_principles/</guid>
      <description>Would that more people followed these seemingly simple principles Summarized from the works of Alice Bailey, particularly A Treatise on White Magic. Above all, practice harmlessness Hold no harmful thoughts. Express no harmful words. Maintain positive harmlessness and constant watchfulness. Engage in no harmful action. Avoid negative harmlessness and tolerance through avoidance. Desire nothing for your separated self Practice and strive for simplicity. Reject materialism. Eliminate possessiveness and self-reference. Look for the sign of divinity in all Focus on the underlying causes, not the outward effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>full humanness</title>
      <link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/full_humanness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/full_humanness/</guid>
      <description>A.H. Maslow coined a number of terms that have come into common parlance beyond academic psychology , including &amp;ldquo;hierarchy of needs&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;self-actualization&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;peak experience&amp;rdquo;. In his last book, The Farther Reaches of Human Nature, Maslow uses the term &amp;ldquo;full humanness&amp;rdquo; to describe psychologically healthy and mature people&amp;ndash; those who are self-actualized and beyond. But what defines a self-actualized person? And what lies beyond self-actualization?
Maslow understood the inherent difficulty of explicitly answering such subjective questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix Affirmations</title>
      <link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/phoenix_affirmations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/phoenix_affirmations/</guid>
      <description>Christianity has gone through a number of significant metamorphoses over the last two millennia, some of them radical enough to permanently change the nature of the West&amp;rsquo;s foremost religion. Another radical change is beginning to swell through the sea of mainstream Christianity as increasing numbers of thoughtful Christians challenge the prevailing doctrines of separation and exclusion, preferring instead to focus on the personal change that comes from a sincere attempt to emulate the life of Jesus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
