<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>speculations on tertium quid</title><link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/categories/speculations/</link><description>Recent content in speculations on tertium quid</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/categories/speculations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>uncivilization</title><link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/dark_mountain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/dark_mountain/</guid><description>When will industrial civilization begin to decline? How long before it is considered an historical relic? Paul Kingsnorth and Dougald Hine&amp;rsquo;s 2009 essay Uncivilization, The Dark Mountain Manifesto argues that our industrial civilization faces a progressive and inevitable decline. Civilizations throughout history have come and gone, they point out, and ours will be no different. Indeed, Kingsnorth and Hine believe that decline has already begun. Critical resource depletion, exploding world population, global warming: any one of them could lead to a system failure; together they virtually guarantee it.</description></item><item><title>spiritual frameworks</title><link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/spiritual_frameworks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/spiritual_frameworks/</guid><description>Is the world, reality, very, very different from what most of us have been taught through modern science? Could non-physical properties (mind, spirit, or other) Provisionally interchangeable terms include mind, spirit, Tao, be as fundamental as charge or mass? Can ancient traditions and mystical perspectives contribute to a more complete picture of the way the universe really is than our current physicalist conception?
According to the scientific models, explanations and narratives that dominate contemporary Western thought, the answer to these questions is a resounding &amp;ldquo;No.</description></item></channel></rss>