<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on tertium quid</title>
    <link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on tertium quid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Nagel</title>
      <link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/thomas_nagel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/thomas_nagel/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Nagel is a leading and articulate critic of reductionist materialism, the dominant worldview in modern secular society. In his 2012 Mind &amp;amp; Cosmos: Why the Neo-Darwinian Conception of Nature is Almost Certainly Wrong, Nagel argues that we need a new, radically different narrative from the dominant scientistic worldview of reductive materialism, contrasting it against theism. Although he takes a relatively broad brush to the concept of theism, he acknowledges that belief in God as fundamental to the universe remains a major alternative to the materialist worldview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physicalism</title>
      <link>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/physicalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs1myers.github.io/hugoTufte/articles/physicalism/</guid>
      <description>“The most important and exceedingly difficult task of our time is to work on the construction of a new idea of reality.”
— Wolfgang Pauli
Almost a century after the initial discoveries of the quantum nature of matter, and many decades after they were confirmed beyond serious question, even many well-educated people do not know that quantum physics appears to have upended a conception of reality that has been in place since the 17th century.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
